uship.com 2019-07-29

# Privacy Policy – Help Center

**Overview**

Your privacy is very important to all of us at uShip. We have established this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”)  to explain to you how your personal information is protected, collected and used. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable such as your name, address, phone number, and email address that is not otherwise publicly available. 

The privacy practices of this statement apply to our services available under the domain and subdomains of www.uShip.com (the "Site") owned and operated by uShip, Inc (“uShip”, “we”, “our”, “us”).

uShip, Inc is the controller of your Personal Data and responsible for the collection, processing and disclosure of your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy unless expressly specified otherwise.

By visiting this website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree, please do not use or access our site.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the uShip User Agreement.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently.

**Personal Data we collect**

In general, you can browse the Site without providing us with any of personal information about yourself. You don’t have to create an account to use some of the uShip services, such as viewing public uShip profiles or public listings. However even when browsing, uShip may receive some personal information from you, like the device you’re using and your IP address.

In order to use most services or features on the Site, you must first complete the registration form and create a username and password. During the registration process, you are required to give contact information such as name, address, phone number, and email address. Note, once you agree to provide us with personal information, you are no longer anonymous to us.

If you choose to use our services, we may require you to provide contact and identity information, billing information, and other personal information as indicated on the forms throughout the Site. Under some circumstances we may require some additional financial information. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature.

If you choose to list, quote, or match on the Site, we collect information about your activity and behavior. We also collect other users’ comments about you in our feedback area.

Additionally, as part of the registration process, uShip allows members registering as a service provider the option to submit certain commercial information such as a commercial service provider’s license number, DOT number, Motor Carrier (MC) number, and/or any other authority a service provider chooses to include. It is up to each member individually to provide this information. uShip will not validate this information but will allow uShip’s 3rd party partners, SaferWatch and SaferWatch CertData, provided by Assure Assist, to access this information in order to obtain relevant information such as authority, insurance coverages and other business information as provided in FMCSA records and other information sources.

Only service providers that submit such commercial, identifying information on the uShip site will be eligible to be officially SaferWatch Monitored, which is signified by a seal on the member profile. This seal and all other public information that a service provider submits can be viewed by other members on the member’s profile page under the About Me section. At any point in time a service provider can choose to opt out of the 3rd party SaferWatch verification program from their uShip account within the edit profile section.

If you choose to post messages on our community discussion forums, Shipment Listing Q&A boards, or leave feedback for other members, we will collect that information you provide to us. We retain this information as necessary to resolve disputes, provide customer support and troubleshoot problems as permitted by law. See “Community Discussion Forums” section below.

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on the Site. If you choose to participate, we will request certain personal information, including your email address, from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information and demographic information. We will not share the personal information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

If you choose to participate in the Bring Your Own Rates program, you will be asked to provide your login credentials for your carrier accounts as part of the enrollment process. uShip collects this information for the sole purpose of uploading your rates to the uShip Platform. All information provided is protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Log Files**

As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. ~~~~

We track trends in users’ usage and volume statistics to create a more efficient and usable site, and to determine areas of the site that could be improved to enhance the user experience.

Log files are used on the website, and in any link to the website from an email.

**Tracking Technologies  **

Technologies such as: cookies and similar technologies are used by uShip and our marketing partners, affiliates, and customer support and fraud prevention service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember user preferences and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.  For more information please visit our Cookie Policy _[here](https://help.uship.com/hc/articles/360003016434)_. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

**Behavioral Targeting/Re-targeting**

We partner with third parties to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies and similar technologies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking _[here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)_ (or if located in the European Union click _[here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)_ ). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**How we use your personal data**

We collect and use your data principally for the following purposes:

  * Provide services and features that are most likely to meet your needs and facilitate the services you request
  * Customize your experience and the content, products, and services offered to you
  * Verify the accuracy of your name, address, and other information
  * Bill you for your use of our services and collect fees owed
  * Provide support for your transactions, products, and services you use
  * Assist you to resolve disputes
  * Comply with legal requirements
  * Inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates
  * Provide targeted advertising, including the use of re-targeting technology
  * Measure consumer interest in our products and services
  * Detect and protect us against error, fraud, and other criminal activity and enforce our User Agreement
  * Look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes and identify users using multiple usernames or aliases
  * Compare and review your personal information for errors, omissions, and accuracy
  * Conduct internal research on our users’ demographics, interest, and behavior to better understand, protect, and serve you and our community
  * Improve our marketing and promotional efforts, analyze site usage, improve our content and product offerings, and customize the Site's content, layout, and services
  * Collect personal information on behalf of our payment processors in order to meet compliance obligations, such as Know Your Customer.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure  **

As a matter of policy, we do not sell, rent or share any of your personal information, including your email address, to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. The profile you create on the Site will be publicly accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal. However, the following describes some of the ways that your personal information may be disclosed in the normal scope of business to provide our services.

**uShip Community:** Your uShip username is displayed throughout the Site and is therefore available to the public. All of your activities on the Site will be identifiable to your username. Other people can see your quotes, shipments you have listed, your feedback rating and associated comments, your postings on the site, and so on. Therefore, if you associate your name with your username, the people you have revealed your name to will be able to personally identify your uShip activities. If you are involved in a transaction, we have features that allow parties to the transaction to view your email address and obtain your contact information to help complete the transaction. Further, we may send out notices to you or other community members regarding suspicious activity or policy violations on the site. Additionally, we may share your written correspondence, including emails to the other party to your transaction as part of the dispute resolutions process. To request removal of your personal information from the uShip community, contact us at our contact information found below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**External Service Providers:** There may be separate services offered by third parties that we refer to as external service providers that may be complementary to your use of the site. If you choose to use these separate services, disclose information to the external service providers, and/or grant them permission to collect information about you, then their use of your information is governed by their privacy policy. We do not disclose your personal information, including your email address, to external service providers unless you provide your explicit consent. With your consent we may provide some of your personal information to the external service provider offering such services, for your convenience. To prevent our disclosure of your personal information to an external service provider, you can decline such consent or simply not use their services. Because we do not control the privacy practices of these third parties, you should evaluate their practices before deciding to use their services. Examples of external service providers include _[McGriff, Seibels& Williams of Oregon, Inc.](http://www.mcgriff.com/)_ and _[Roanoke](http://www.roanoketrade.com/)_ which provide the uShip Cargo Insurance and facilitate the claims process.

**Internal Service Providers for Our Operations:** We may use third parties that we refer to as internal service providers to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of the business (sometimes utilizing framing techniques), product and service operations that we provide to you and therefore we may provide some of your personal information, including your email address, directly to these internal service providers. Any sensitive information that is transmitted to internal service providers involved in any payment processing functions will be encrypted or tokenized. These internal service providers' are subject to confidentiality agreements with us and other legal restrictions that prohibit their use of the information we provide them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced uShip related operation, unless you have explicitly agreed or given your prior permission to them for additional uses. If you provide additional information to an internal service provider directly, then their use of your personal information is governed by their applicable privacy policy. Examples of internal service providers include Stripe which is involved in payment processing functions, PayPal which is involved in the credit card processing function, and Grizella’s SaferWatch tool (including SaferWatch CertData, provided by Assure Assist) which monitors all participating service provider’s licensure and insurance information.

**Frames:** Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to _[http://www.uship.com](http://www.uship.com/)_.

**Legal Requests:** uShip cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as: intellectual property rights, fraud and other rights, to help protect you and the uShip community from bad actors. Therefore, in response to a verified request by law enforcement or other government officials relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your name, city, state, telephone number, email address, user history, fraud complaints, and quoting and listing history without a subpoena. Without limiting the above, in an effort to respect your privacy and our ability to keep the community free from bad actors, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement or other government officials without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of information is necessary to: prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss; or report suspected illegal activity.

Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose personal information, including your email address, to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private. See “Security Section” below.

We collect your location-based information for the purpose of locating a place that you may be searching for in your area. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service. You may opt-out of location based services at any time by editing the setting at the device level or by emailing us at _[privacy@uShip.com](mailto:privacy@uShip.com)_.

**Communications from the Site**

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, and promotions, as well as a newsletter. You are signed up for these emails at registration and you may unsubscribe at any time by going to your account tab and opting out of the emails, or by following the directions to unsubscribe in the email.

Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe from each of these communications when we ask for it. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at _[privacy@uShip.com](mailto:privacy@uShip.com)_.

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

Based upon the personal information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your email address, username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. Email is the primary means of communication between members doing transactions on the site and you must be able to receive this information to use uShip properly.

**Links to Other Sites  **

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by uShip. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Web site.

Some portions of the uShip platform implement Google Maps mapping services, including Google Maps API(s). Your use of Google Maps is subject to _[Google’s Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms)_ and _[Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy)_ , as may be amended by Google from time to time.

**Community Discussion Forums**

If you use a bulletin board on the Site, you should be aware that any personal information, including your email address, you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. All other information pertaining to the collection and use of information can be found in the _[Discussion Forum rules](https://help.uship.com/hc/articles/206501327)_. To request removal of your personal information from the uShip community, contact us at _[privacy@uShip.com](mailto:privacy@uShip.com)_. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. We may post your testimonial along with your first name and last initial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at _[privacy@uShip.com](mailto:privacy@uShip.com)_.

  **Social Media Connections & Features**

uShip may allow users to access Facebook Connect to interact with friends and to share on Facebook through wall and friends’ news feeds. If you are already logged into uShip and Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to merge your profiles. If you are already logged into uShip but not logged into Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to enter your Facebook credentials or to “Sign up for Facebook.” By proceeding, you are allowing the uShip site to access your information and you are agreeing to the Facebook Terms of Use in your use of the uShip site.

Conversely, if you are not currently registered as a uShip user and you click on “Sign in using Facebook” you will first be asked to enter your Facebook credentials and then be given the option to register and join uShip. Once you register on the uShip site and Connect with Facebook, you will be able to automatically post recent activity back to Facebook. You have the option to disable Facebook Connect at any time by logging into your profile and clicking on “My Facebook Profile.” Further, you can edit privacy settings for the reviews that appear on Facebook or disconnect this service by visiting the Facebook Application Settings page.

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook 'Like' button and widgets, such as the 'Share this' button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect information such as your IP address and which page you are visiting on our site, and they may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing them.

**Access to Personal Information**

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. You may request this information by contacting _[privacy@uship.com](mailto:privacy@uship.com)_. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

If you are a registered user, you may correct or rectify your data at any time. We provide you with tools to access, correct, delete or modify the personal data you provided to us through your member Account page or by contacting our Customer Operations team at _[uShip Member Support](http://www.uship.com/support/)_. 

If you no longer desire to use our service you can deactivate your account at any time by making the change on your member Account page or by contacting by contacting our Customer Operations team at _[uShip Member Support](http://www.uship.com/support/)_. You can also manage your privacy settings by accessing your Communication Preferences through your Member Account page.

If you deactivate your account, or request that your account be deactivated please keep in mind that search engines may still retain copies of your public information in line with their retention policies. You will need to contact those 3rd parties directly to remove your information.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.  You information until any and all compliance obligations are met.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information, including your email address, submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**International Privacy Laws  **

If you are visiting the Site outside of the United States, please be aware that you are sending information to the United States where our servers are located. That information may then be transferred within the United States or back out of the United States to other countries outside of your country of residence.  These countries (including the United States) may not have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in your country of residence; however, our collection, storage, and protection of your Personal Information will be governed by this Privacy Policy. 

**EU-US Privacy Shield**

uShip participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. We are committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and the United Kingdom, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.

uShip is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. We comply with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and the United Kingdom, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, we are subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Business Transitions**

In the event uShip goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information, including your email address, will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

**Changes in this Privacy Policy  
**If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy policy on our website and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

**Contact Us**

_If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy or to exercise your rights regarding your personal information, please contact us at _[privacy@uShip.com](mailto:privacy@uShip.com)_ or by mail at the address below. _

_uShip, Inc._  
 _205 E Riverside Dr_  
 _Austin, TX 78704_  
 _United States_

_If you are located in the EEA, and you believe that we have not been able to assist you with your complaint or concern about our use of your information, you have the right to contact your local supervisory authority with your concerns._

_Last Revised Date_ _: January 11, 2019_
